Guide to the Artists Collection, ca. 1902-1939
Department of Special Collections
Artists Collection,
ca. 1902-1939
Special Collections M0136
Artists
.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Various Sources
Scope and Content
Summary: Single items and small collections of letters by or about artists, some catalogs and examples of their work. Includes material on painters, sculptors, architects, and photographers.
Container List
- Beard, Daniel Carter 1850-1941 (Painter, illustrator) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1939 June 19tls to Ray Lyman Wilbur.
- [Boni, Giacomo] 1859-1925 (Italian architect & archeologist) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1939 June 19als to Ray Lyman Wilbur.
- Borglum, Gutzon 1871-1941 (Full name: John Gutzon de la Methe) (Sculptor) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1914Printed catalog of exhibit, autographed in 1919 to F.B. Loomis
- Christy, Howard Chandler 1873-1952 (Illustrator, painter) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1902 May 2Autograph.
- Craig, Edward Gordon 1872- [?] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1939Designs for bookplate of Marion MacKaye, printed.
- Cruikshank, George 1792-1878 (Caricaturist) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - n.d.Als to Pelham
- Genthe, Arnold 1869-1942 (Photographer) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1927 Jan. 25Photogram to MRs. B.E. Alanson.
- Hoffman, Malvina 1887- (Sculptor) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1929 Mar. 28Tls to Mrs. Sloss.
- Keith, William 1839-1911 (Artist) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1. 1904 Sept. 14Als & cvr. to Mrs. Sloss.
  - 2. 1904 Oct. 17Als & cvr. to Mrs. Sloss.
  - 3. 1904 Dec. 24Als & cvr. to Mrs. Sloss.
- Kent, Rockwell 1882- (Artist) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1935 June 22Als & cvr. to Alexander Goldenweiser.
- [Lisser, Bertha] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - n.d.Als to Mrs. Sloss.
- Matisse, Henri 1869-1954 (Artist) (Box 1, Folder 11a)
  - Whimsical chair, ca. 1923Pencil drawing.
- Paget, Fredericks J. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 1. Als to Mrs. [Leuschner].
  - 2. Designs for two book jackets.
- Putnam, Arthur 1873-1930 (Sculptor) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 1910 Feb. 18Als to Mrs. Sloss & cvr.
- Raphael, Joseph (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - n.d.Als to Mrs. Sloss
- Severn, Walter (Son of Joseph Severn) (Box 1, Folder 14a)
  - Als 1893 July 21re: portrait of John Keats by his father.
- Velde, Henry Van de 1863- (Architect) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1935 Apr. 22Als to M. Lebrun in French with typed translation.
- Woodward, Robert Strong (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 1933 Sept. 6Als & cvr. to Miss J. Hitchcock & newspaper reproduction of painting.